<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Visit Somerset</string>

    <string name="wells">Wells Cathedral</string>
    <string name="wells_description">
        Wells Cathedral is an Anglican church in Wells, Somerset England. It is the seat of the Bishop of Bath and Wells. Its construction started in 1170 and the Cathedral was dedicated in 1239.
        \n\nWells Cathedral has been described as \“the most poetic of the English Cathedrals\”. Much of the structure is in Early English architecture. Many mouldings look almost like sculptures. The carved capitals are done in a foliate style known as \“stiff leaf\”. This adds to their lively view. The eastern end has kept much original glass, which is rare in England. The exterior has a splendid Early English façade (~front) and a large central tower.
        \n\nThe first church was established on the site in 705. Construction of the present building began in the 10th century under Anglo-Saxon rule, but was later transformed under the Normans. It was largely complete at the time of its dedication in 1239. It has been expanded and renovated several times since then and has been designated by English Heritage as a grade I listed building.
        \n\nThe present structure was begun under the direction of Bishop Reginald de Bohun, who died in 1184. Wells Cathedral dates mainly from the late twelfth and early thirteenth centuries; the nave and transept are masterpieces of Early English architecture. It was largely complete at the time of its dedication in 1239.
        \n\nThe bishop responsible for the construction was Jocelyn de Wells, one of the bishops at the signing of Magna Carta. Jocelyn\'s buildings included the Bishop\'s Palace, a choristers\' school, a grammar school, a hospital for travellers and a chapel. He also built a manor at Wookey, near Wells. The master mason associated with Jocelyn was Elias of Dereham (died 1246). Jocelyn lived to see the church dedicated but, despite much lobbying of Rome, died in 1242. Cathedral status was granted in 1245. Masons continued with the enrichment of the West Front until about 1260.
        \n\nKing John was excommunicated between 1209 and 1213. During this time, work on the cathedral was suspended. In this period, building methods advanced so that bigger blocks of masonry could be moved and put into the walls. The effect of this advance can be seen on the walls of the cathedral; at a point in the building\'s walls, the blocks of stone increase in size. By the time the building was finished, including the Chapter House (1306), it already seemed too small for the developing liturgy, in particular the increasingly grand processions.
        \n\nA new spate of building was therefore started by Bishop John Drokensford. He heightened the central tower and began a dramatic eight-sided Lady chapel at the far east end, finished by 1326. Thomas of Whitney was the master mason.
        \n\nBishop Ralph of Shrewsbury followed. He continued the eastward extension of the quire. He also built Vicars\' Close and the Vicars\' Hall, to give the men of the choir a secure place to live and dine, away from the town with all its temptations. He enjoyed an uneasy relationship with the citizens of Wells, partly because of his imposition of taxes. He surrounded his palace with crenellated walls and a moat and drawbridge. The Palace was now a castle.
        \n\nThe appointment of William Wynford as master mason in 1365 marked another period of activity. He was one of the foremost architects of his time and, apart from Wells, was engaged in work for the king at Windsor and at New College, Oxford University and Winchester Cathedral. Under Bishop John Harewell, he built the south-west tower of the West Front and designed the north west, which was built to match in the early 15th century. Inside the building he filled in the early English lancet windows with delicate tracery.
        \n\nIn the fourteenth century, the central piers (upright supports) of the crossing (where the building forms a cross) started sinking under the weight of the crossing tower. \'Scissor arches\' were inserted to brace and stabilize the piers as a unit. The building was now complete, and it looked much as it does today.
    </string>
    <string name="wells_img_author">David Iliff</string>
    <string name="wells_img_license">CC BY-SA 3.0</string>


    <string name="roman">Roman Baths</string>
    <string name="roman_description">
        The Roman Baths are well-preserved thermae in the city of Bath, Somerset, England. A temple was constructed on the site between 60 and 70 AD in the first few decades of Roman Britain. Its presence led to the development of the small Roman urban settlement known as Aquae Sulis around the site. The Roman baths—designed for public bathing—were used until the end of Roman rule in Britain in the 5th century AD. According to the Anglo-Saxon Chronicle, the original Roman baths were in ruins a century later. The area around the natural springs was redeveloped several times during the Early and Late Middle Ages.
        \n\nThe Roman Baths are preserved in four main features: the Sacred Spring, the Roman Temple, the Roman Bath House, and a museum which holds artefacts from Aquae Sulis. However, all buildings at street level date from the 19th century. It is a major tourist attraction in the UK, and together with the Grand Pump Room, receives more than 1.3 million visitors annually. Visitors can tour the baths and museum but cannot enter the water.
        \n\nThe water is sourced from rainfall on the nearby Mendip Hills, which then percolates down through limestone aquifers to a depth of between 2,700 and 4,300 metres (8,900 and 14,100 ft). Geothermal energy raises the water temperature here to between 69 and 96 °C (156.2 and 204.8 °F). Under pressure, the heated water rises along fissures and faults in the limestone, until it bubbles up from the ground into the baths. This process is similar to an enhanced geothermal system, which also makes use of the high pressures and temperatures below the Earth\'s crust. Hot water at a temperature of 46 °C (114.8 °F) rises here at the rate of 1,170,000 litres (257,364 imp gal) every day, from a geological fault (the Pennyquick fault). In 1982 a new spa water bore-hole was sunk, providing a clean and safe supply of spa water for drinking in the Pump Room.
        \n\nWater quality
        \n\nBath was charged with responsibility for the hot springs in a Royal Charter of 1591 granted by Elizabeth I. This duty has now passed to Bath and North East Somerset Council, who monitor pressure, temperature and flow rates. The thermal waters contain sodium, calcium, chloride and sulphate ions in high concentrations.
        \n\nThe Roman Baths are no longer used for bathing. In October 1978, a young girl swimming in the restored Roman Bath with the Bath Dolphins, a local swimming club, contracted naegleriasis and died, leading to the closure of the bath for several years. Tests showed Naegleria fowleri, a deadly pathogen, in the water. The newly constructed Thermae Bath Spa nearby, and the refurbished Cross Bath, allow modern-day bathers to experience the waters via a series of more recently drilled boreholes.
        \n\nPreservation
        \n\nThe late 19th-century carvings of Roman Emperors and Governors of Roman Britain on the terrace overlooking the Great Bath are particularly susceptible to the effect of acid rain and are protected with a wash of a sacrificial shelter coat every few years. Exhibits within the temple precincts are susceptible to warm air which had the effect of drawing corrosive salts out of the Roman stonework. To help reduce this, a new ventilation system was installed in 2006.
        \n\nIn 2009 a grant of £90,000 was made to Bath and North East Somerset Council to contribute towards the cost of re-developing displays and improving access to the Roman Baths, by the Department for Culture, Media and Sport/Wolfson Fund, which was established to promote improvements in Museums and Galleries in England. Subsequent grants have funded further work on the exhibition design and layout by London-based specialist firm, Event Communications.
    </string>
    <string name="roman_img_author">Diego Delso</string>
    <string name="roman_img_license">CC BY-SA 4.0</string>

    <string name="bridgwater">Bridgwater Carnival</string>
    <string name="bridgwater_description">
        The original Bridgwater celebrations consisted of a large bonfire at the Cornhill. Built out of a large wooden boat, around one hundred tar barrels were added, together with just about anything else available which could be burned. This tradition was stopped due to lack of old wooden boats to burn, and because a number of good boats were thrown onto the fire and burnt by over-enthusiastic revellers.
        \n\nEffigies or \"guys\" representing the gunpowder plot instigators were added to the fire by local groups of people known as gangs. It would seem it was these gangs who started the trend towards a procession, as they paraded their guys towards the bonfire. As years passed by, the tradition was continued and the annual celebration became more and more elaborate, involving costumes, and music, until the key feature of the event was a large carnival procession.
        \n\nThe local people who dressed up and took part in the event were known as Masqueraders or Features - terms still used today to describe the parade participants.
        \n\nThere were no parades during the Second World War, but a local carnival enthusiast William Henry Edwin Lockyer, also known as \"Nosey,\" walked the carnival route for six years with a group known as The Kilties, to keep the tradition alive.
        \n\nIn 2020 and 2021, the procession featuring carts was cancelled due to the COVID-19 Pandemic. To replace the 2020 Bridgwater procession, a live stream was held on carnival night showing some of the best carnival carts over the years. In 2021, smaller Masquerade parades were put on in Bridgwater and Burnham-On-Sea, which featured most of the clubs in the previous years\’ carnivals, entering with walking entries on a smaller route.
        \n\nSquibbing
        \n\nIn addition to the carnival procession, the tradition of \"squibbing\" still occurs after the procession ends. A squib locally is a firework which is held aloft by a person known as a \"squibber\" on the end of a long wooden handle called a \"cosh\". One hundred squibbers stand in line in Bridgwater town centre, making an unusual but impressive sight for visitors who crowd the High Street.
        \n\nOriginally, the squibs were made specially for the carnival and were known as the Bridgwater Squib, and culminated with a large bang as each squib extinguished. With modern Health and Safety concerns, it has become difficult to purchase such squibs, and owing to the rising cost of insurance, the present-day squibs have no bang.
        \n\nLines of flammable liquid are also run along the ground by the squibbers and lit to add to the spectacle. Visitors often think the whole sight looks a little dangerous, but the event is well-organised and nobody has been hurt to date.
        \n\nModern Times
        \n\nThe Bridgwater carnival first modernised in 1881 and was originally lit by lamps; electric lights were first introduced in 1913.
        \n\nBridgwater carnival now consists of a display of over 40 large vehicles up to 100 feet (30 m) long, festooned with dancers and up to 22,000 lightbulbs, that follows a 2.5-mile (4 km) route over two to three hours. 2005 included the Masquerade 2000 entrants from Notting Hill Carnival.
        \n\nBridgwater now attracts around 150,000 people from around the West Country, UK, and globally. Parking from the M5 is well sign-posted and plentiful, and managed by the committee in association with Avon and Somerset Police. Public access grandstands were introduced in the mid-1990s, which have increased in popularity over recent years.
        \n\nThe carnival\'s purpose is to raise money for local charities from money collection carts in the procession. Between 2003 and 2007, around £115,000 was raised at Bridgwater Carnival.
        \n\nIn 2010, the Heritage Lottery Fund awarded the Carnival in Somerset Promotion Project £41,000 to promote and conserve carnival heritage. The project aims to raise awareness of the history of the carnivals within schools and the local community.
    </string>
    <string name="bridgwater_img_author">Geof Sheppard</string>
    <string name="bridgwater_img_license">CC BY-SA 4.0</string>

    <string name="cheddar">Cheddar Gorge</string>
    <string name="cheddar_description">
        Cheddar Gorge is a limestone gorge in the Mendip Hills, near the village of Cheddar, Somerset, England. The gorge is the site of the Cheddar show caves, where Britain\'s oldest complete human skeleton, Cheddar Man, estimated to be 9,000 years old, was found in 1903. Older remains from the Upper Late Palaeolithic era (12,000–13,000 years ago) have been found. The caves, produced by the activity of an underground river, contain stalactites and stalagmites. The gorge is part of a Site of Special Scientific Interest called Cheddar Complex.
        \n\nCheddar Gorge, including the caves and other attractions, has become a tourist destination. In a 2005 poll of Radio Times readers, following its appearance on the television programme Seven Natural Wonders (2005), Cheddar Gorge was named as the second greatest natural wonder in Britain, surpassed only by Dan yr Ogof caves. The gorge attracts about 500,000 visitors per year.
        \n\nGeology
        \n\nCheddar is a gorge lying on the southern edge of the Mendip Hills. The maximum depth of the gorge is 137 m (449 ft), with a near-vertical cliff-face to the south, and steep grassy slopes to the north. The B3135 road runs along the bottom of the gorge.
        \n\nThe area is underlain by Black Rock slate, Burrington Oolite, and Clifton Down Limestone of the Carboniferous Limestone Series, which contain ooliths and fossil debris, on top of Old Red Sandstone and by dolomitic conglomerate of the Keuper. Evidence for Variscan orogeny is seen in the sheared rock and cleaved shales. In many places, weathering of these strata has resulted in the formation of immature calcareous soils.
        \n\nThe gorge was originally formed 225 million years ago, during the Triassic Period. The Mendip Carboniferous limestone stood as a series of \'whale-backed\' hills. At that time, the UK had a warm arid climate, not dissimilar to northern Africa today. Occasionally, \'flash floods\' caused huge volumes of water to run off the hills and form Wadis - steep-sided gorges. Cheddar Gorge and its near neighbor, Burrington Combe, are exhumed Wadis. They were originally filled with Triassic rocks that may have been eroded out by meltwaters at the end of the last Ice Age. Parts of Burrington Combe still have these Triassic rocks, forming an unconformity with the Carboniferous limestones, along their sides and bottom.
        \n\nDuring the ice ages, permafrost blocked the caves with ice and frozen mud and made the limestone impermeable. When this melted during the summers, water was forced to flow on the surface and carved out the softer Triassic rocks, exhuming the wadi. During warmer periods, the water flowed underground through the permeable limestone, creating the caves and leaving the gorge dry, so that today much of the gorge has no river until the underground Cheddar Yeo river emerges in the lower part from Gough\'s Cave. The river is used by Bristol Water, which maintains a series of dams and ponds that supply the nearby Cheddar Reservoir via a 137-centimetre (54 in) diameter pipe that takes water just upstream of the Rotary Club Sensory Garden, a public park in the gorge opposite Jacob\'s Ladder.
        \n\nThe gorge is susceptible to flooding. In the Chew Stoke flood of 1968, the flow of water washed large boulders down the gorge, damaging the café and entrance to Gough\'s Cave and washing away cars. In the cave itself, the flooding lasted for three days. In 2012, the B3135, the road through the gorge, was closed for several weeks following damage to the road surface during extensive flooding.
    </string>
    <string name="cheddar_img_author">Colin Smith</string>
    <string name="cheddar_img_license">CC BY-SA 2.0</string>

    <string name="glastonbury">Glastonbury Tor</string>
    <string name="glastonbury_description">
        Glastonbury Tor is a tor near Glastonbury in the English county of Somerset, topped by the roofless St Michael\'s Tower, a Grade I listed building. The site is managed by the National Trust and has been designated a scheduled monument. The Tor is mentioned in Celtic mythology, particularly in myths linked to King Arthur, and has several other enduring mythological and spiritual associations.
        \n\nThe conical hill of clay and Blue Lias rises from the Somerset Levels. It was formed when surrounding softer deposits were eroded, leaving a hard cap of sandstone exposed. The slopes of the hill are terraced, but the method by which they were formed remains unexplained.
        \n\nArchaeological excavations during the 20th century sought to clarify the background of the monument and church, but some aspects of their history remain unexplained. Artefacts from human visitation have been found, dating from the Iron Age to Roman eras. Several buildings were constructed on the summit during Saxon and early medieval periods; they have been interpreted as an early church and monks\' hermitage. The head of a wheel cross dating from the 10th or 11th century has been recovered. The original wooden church was destroyed by an earthquake in 1275, and the stone Church of St Michael was built on the site in the 14th century. Its tower remains, although it has been restored and partially rebuilt several times.
        \n\nTerraces
        \n\nThe sides of the Tor have seven deep, roughly symmetrical terraces, or lynchets. Their formation remains a mystery, with many possible explanations. They may have been formed as a result of natural differentiation of the layers of Lias stone and clay or used by farmers during the Middle Ages as terraced hills to make ploughing for crops easier. Author Nicholas Mann questions this theory, suggesting that if agriculture were the reason for the terraces, they would be concentrated on the south side, where the sunny conditions would provide a good yield, yet the terraces are equally deep on the northern side, which would provide little benefit. Additionally, none of the other slopes of the island have been terraced.
        \n\nOther explanations have been suggested for the terraces, including the construction of defensive ramparts. Iron Age hill forts, such as the nearby Cadbury Castle in Somerset, show evidence of extensive fortification of their slopes. The normal form of ramparts is a bank and ditch, but there is no evidence of this arrangement on the Tor. South Cadbury had three concentric rings of banks and ditches supporting a 44-acre enclosure, while the Tor has seven rings and limited space on top for community safekeeping. It has been suggested that a defensive function may have been linked with Ponter\'s Ball Dyke, a linear earthwork about a mile east of the Tor. It consists of an embankment with a ditch on the east side. The purpose and provenance of the dyke are unclear. It is possible that it was part of a longer defensive barrier associated with New Ditch, three miles to the southwest, which is built in a similar manner. Ralegh Radford suggested it might be part of a great Celtic sanctuary from around the 3rd century BC, while others, including Philip Rahtz, date it to the post-Roman period and link it to the Dark Age occupation on Glastonbury Tor. The 1970 excavation suggests the 12th century or later. Historian Ronald Hutton also mentions the alternative possibility that the terraces are the remains of a medieval \"spiral walkway\" created for pilgrims to reach the church on the summit, similar to that at Whitby Abbey.
        \n\nAnother suggestion is that the terraces are the remains of a three-dimensional labyrinth, first proposed by Geoffrey Russell in 1968. He suggests that the classical labyrinth, a design found worldwide in the Neolithic, can be transposed onto the Tor so that by walking around the terraces, a person eventually reaches the top in the same pattern. This hypothesis is difficult to evaluate. A labyrinth would likely place the terraces in the Neolithic era, but given the amount of occupation since then, substantial modifications may have occurred by farmers or monks, and conclusive excavations have not been carried out. In a more recent book, Hutton writes that \"the labyrinth does not seem to be an ancient sacred structure.\"

    </string>
    <string name="glastonbury_img_author">Mundo Salvaje Media</string>
    <string name="glastonbury_img_license">CC BY-SA 4.0</string>
</resources>